<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>bash on www.freniche.com</title>
    <link>https://dfreniche.github.io/tags/bash/</link>
    <description>Recent content in bash on www.freniche.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright> </copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dfreniche.github.io/tags/bash/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Less Harsh Xcode Errors</title>
      <link>https://dfreniche.github.io/posts/2021-05-24-less-harsh-xcode-errors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dfreniche.github.io/posts/2021-05-24-less-harsh-xcode-errors/</guid>
      <description>Coding is sometimes hard. We all know this. But dealing with compiler errors is one of the worst parts. You have this idea in your mind, you want to try it quickly and then, 💥 compiler error! You forgot those semicolons! Or you added them and your language doesn&amp;rsquo;t like them! Or that class lacks a constructor!
Whatever the reason, compiler errors are always harsh: we made a mistake, and the compiler is not forgiving.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using a local and global Cocoapods executable</title>
      <link>https://dfreniche.github.io/posts/2020-10-28-using-local-and-global-cocoapod/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dfreniche.github.io/posts/2020-10-28-using-local-and-global-cocoapod/</guid>
      <description>The problem You have a project that uses Cocoapods to solve all your dependencies needs. Everything works OK until one of your coworkers updates his version of Cocoapods (it&amp;rsquo;s never you, it&amp;rsquo;s always one of the others in these kind of stories). Then he makes some changes, and those changes are incompatible with the version you have.
A solution Your team hold a meeting. You all decide settling on a certain version number.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maintain Your Sourcetree Bookmarks Throught Several Machines</title>
      <link>https://dfreniche.github.io/posts/2016-02-29-maintain-your-sourcetree-bookmarks-throught-several-machines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dfreniche.github.io/posts/2016-02-29-maintain-your-sourcetree-bookmarks-throught-several-machines/</guid>
      <description>If you use git, you probable have heard about SourceTree, the superb Atlassian git client, that solves 99% of your day-to-day git needs, connects to Github &amp;amp; Bitbucket repos and works on Mac and Windows. On top of that: it&amp;rsquo;s free, as in beer.
Keep reading this post in the Mobile Jazz Blog</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>