<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on www.freniche.com</title>
    <link>https://dfreniche.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on www.freniche.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright> </copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dfreniche.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The humble assignment operator in Swift</title>
      <link>https://dfreniche.github.io/posts/2020-08-15-the-humble-assignment-operator/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dfreniche.github.io/posts/2020-08-15-the-humble-assignment-operator/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;rsquo;re starting to learn any programming language. From Assemmbler to Clojure, from Swift to COBOL. At some point you&amp;rsquo;ll want to assign a value to a memory position. It can be a constant or a variable. You just want to change that memory position. This is something so basic that CPUs have lots a lots of operations devoted to moving data around: setting the CPU registers, copying blocks of bytes from one place to another, moving data into the stack, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FlatMap for Optionals, took me a while to understand</title>
      <link>https://dfreniche.github.io/posts/2020-08-13-flatmap-optionals/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dfreniche.github.io/posts/2020-08-13-flatmap-optionals/</guid>
      <description>In my last post I wrote about why I think Swift is not a simple language. After all, if you need powerful, expressive constructs you´ll end up having some degree of complexity in there. My critique was more about how they market it as simple for beginners, when sometimes I have to scratch my head to understand some code. I´m dumb as a rock, that&amp;rsquo;s for sure, but have been typing code since ´88.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swift, the simple and easy to learn language?</title>
      <link>https://dfreniche.github.io/posts/2020-07-27-swift-the-not-that-easy-to-learn-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dfreniche.github.io/posts/2020-07-27-swift-the-not-that-easy-to-learn-language/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Kimberly Farmer on Unsplash
Apple markets Swift as The powerful programming language that is also easy to learn.
Nope.
Sorry to break this on you, but Swift is far from easy to learn. This is something I’ve been commenting in the past in Twitter, Slack and private conversations with other devs. To set a baseline, if I say Swift is not easy to learn, what would an easy to learn language look like?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I love listening to music</title>
      <link>https://dfreniche.github.io/posts/2020-07-19-i-love-listening-to-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dfreniche.github.io/posts/2020-07-19-i-love-listening-to-music/</guid>
      <description>I love listening to music. I can’t play any instrument, but I do enjoy listening to each note in a song, identifying the instruments, getting emotional with the lyrics of a music piece. Getting those goosebumps.
Being a product of my time and age, I mostly listen to 80’s and 90’s songs, with some modern additions thrown into the mix. I hate Reggaeton and Trap with the power of a thousand suns, but that’s for a different post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Nef to test and document libraries</title>
      <link>https://dfreniche.github.io/posts/2020-07-12-nef/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dfreniche.github.io/posts/2020-07-12-nef/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes I need to use a third party library (usually added to my project using CocoaPods) so I quickly grab it, integrate it and start adding code. But some frameworks are more difficult to understand, learn and use than others.
Recently I’ve been learning RxSwift. I learn by trying out some code while reading or watching videos. I really need to code for it to stick. I can create a full-blown project and add that RxSwift dependency via CocoaPods, but what I don’t want it’s all the other stuff that comes with a project: storyboards, ViewControllers, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We don&#39;t need quotas in tech</title>
      <link>https://dfreniche.github.io/posts/2019-15-10-i-also-had-bias/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dfreniche.github.io/posts/2019-15-10-i-also-had-bias/</guid>
      <description>Many, many years ago I was in the &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t want women/PoC/minorities quotas in Tech. That&amp;rsquo;s not needed. After all, this is a meritocracy, so if you&amp;rsquo;re good at programming that&amp;rsquo;s all that counts&amp;rdquo;.
Boy was I wrong&amp;hellip;
It&amp;rsquo;s a meritocracy if you don&amp;rsquo;t feel attacked. If you feel safe. If you can be yourself. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have to waste that much time/energy pretending to be a different person. If you don&amp;rsquo;t hate going to the bathroom and finding someone else inside.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you remember del.icio.us?</title>
      <link>https://dfreniche.github.io/posts/2019-07-21-do-you-remember-delicious/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dfreniche.github.io/posts/2019-07-21-do-you-remember-delicious/</guid>
      <description>Yep, this is old. Del.icio.us was a link-sharing / personal link storage system that existed wayyyy in the past. Before Chrome, Firefox, Safari or Edge had profiles and the ability to store your favorite pages and access them from different computers.
Because that was the problem Delicious solved: accessing your favorite links from your work’s computer or at home. Back when that was cool.
Today, reviewing my old accounts and changing passwords I bumped into it, and logged in just to see if it still works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My standup Shell Script</title>
      <link>https://dfreniche.github.io/posts/2019-07-10-my-standup-shell-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dfreniche.github.io/posts/2019-07-10-my-standup-shell-script/</guid>
      <description>At Teamwork’s Mobile Team we hold a Standup meeting every day, at 11:00 AM Irish Time. That’s Noon for me, here in Spain. And more than a Standup is a “Status Update” to let other members of the Mobile sub-teams know roughly what I’m doing and if I have some errand to run, or won’t be available for several hours, etc. It&amp;rsquo;s also a good way to keep the connection with the rest of the team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reaching iCloud from the command line</title>
      <link>https://dfreniche.github.io/posts/2019-07-09-reaching-icloud-from-the-command-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dfreniche.github.io/posts/2019-07-09-reaching-icloud-from-the-command-line/</guid>
      <description>Recently I’ve abandoned Dropbox and switched over iCloud. I’ll talk about the reasons in another post, but sounds crazy to me that right now iCloud is a better option than Dropbox in the Mac&amp;hellip;
I have different things stored in my Cloud Storage. Some repos from unfinished projects, living proof of that moment’s abandoned hype, some personal documents, all my iPad Apps docs, shared configuration for Bash / Zsh and lots of small scripts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing again</title>
      <link>https://dfreniche.github.io/posts/2019-06-28-writing-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dfreniche.github.io/posts/2019-06-28-writing-again/</guid>
      <description>This time in English!
OK, I love to write. My old blog (in Spanish) is a testament to this. Lots of words were written there over many, many years. I also like to write fiction, but I’m so ashamed of everything I figure out that often I just compose things in my mind, where Facebook can’t read them (for now at least)
Wanted to write again for a while now, but been agonizing (and procrastinating over) deciding the most stupid of things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Recover A Deleted Git Stash</title>
      <link>https://dfreniche.github.io/posts/2016-08-30-how-to-recover-a-deleted-git-stash/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dfreniche.github.io/posts/2016-08-30-how-to-recover-a-deleted-git-stash/</guid>
      <description>This is a scary story, not like a horror movie, but frightening enough to give any developer the shivers. The story goes a little something like this…
A customer directs your attention to a bug you know you’ve solved, tested and shipped. You fixed it one day ago so the bug can’t be there, the customer must be wrong?!
After running the application, waiting to not see the bug, it’s there again!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not Good At Teamwork</title>
      <link>https://dfreniche.github.io/posts/2016-08-10-not-good-at-teamwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dfreniche.github.io/posts/2016-08-10-not-good-at-teamwork/</guid>
      <description>Are you good at teamwork? Yes, of course
 Who would say something different at a job interview? This question, or something similar, almost always appears when you are talking with people you want to work with at a new company. It’s natural to ask, because almost every project is a team effort, with many people involved: designers, project managers, product owners, customers, users of the product, developers etc. They call it “stakeholders” meaning “people interested in building something together”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maintain Your Sourcetree Bookmarks Throught Several Machines</title>
      <link>https://dfreniche.github.io/posts/2016-02-29-maintain-your-sourcetree-bookmarks-throught-several-machines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dfreniche.github.io/posts/2016-02-29-maintain-your-sourcetree-bookmarks-throught-several-machines/</guid>
      <description>If you use git, you probable have heard about SourceTree, the superb Atlassian git client, that solves 99% of your day-to-day git needs, connects to Github &amp;amp; Bitbucket repos and works on Mac and Windows. On top of that: it&amp;rsquo;s free, as in beer.
Keep reading this post in the Mobile Jazz Blog</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>